while barbells get a lot of the
attention because of how much weight you
can load onto one
kettlebells are beasts in and of
themselves because of the time under
tension as well as the different angles
that you can hit
if you're looking to turn up the heat in
the weight room or in your home look no
further than a good old kettlebell i was
able to get my hands on one of the most
popular models from rogue so today i'm
going to break down my findings for you
guys but enough with all the chit chat
let's get straight to it
[Music]
what's up everybody it's jake back in
the barbin garage gym and for today's
video i have a rogue kettlebell in this
review i'm going to tell you everything
you need to know about these kettlebells
from the price and some of the features
as well as the pros and cons you'll
experience while working out with them
and of course what would i be doing if i
didn't include who should or should not
buy one of these
now before i get really started though i
got to let you know we've reviewed a lot
of kettlebells on barbin.com if you want
to browse our best list just go ahead
and search barbin best kettlebells and
you can find out for yourself which ones
we like the best
[Music]
okay so let's talk about what i like
about these kettlebells well with all
gym equipment texture matters right well
that's something that rogue has got
going on here with these kettlebells the
powder coat gives it a really nice feel
it gives you a really good grip on its
own it's also going to mix well with
chalk if that's something you like to
use and it's not too rough on your skin
which is a really nice touch too this is
one single piece of iron ore so there's
no welding here to hold the belt and the
handle together there's no plastic caps
or plugs
none of that that you'll find often with
kettlebells of lesser quality so this is
really durable it's going to last you a
really long time you don't have to worry
about the connection with the handle and
the bell
ever coming loose
the handle right here is 1.4 inches in
diameter it's going to give you a nice
solid grip i really like how they're
color coded that's pretty common but
this blue right here really pops out in
my eyes which is really nice i also
really like the flat base design there's
no seams there's no ridges there's
nothing down here interfering with the
kettlebell and whatever surface you go
to store yours on so
shouldn't experience much wobble if any
whatsoever
plus there's 18 different weight options
for you to choose from now those are
going to range from nine pounds up to
203 pounds that's in non-intervals so
it's going to vary you know from bell to
bell and the gap and the weight
but there really is an option out there
for basically everyone to choose from
[Music]
okay so what about those cons that i
noticed with these kettlebells
i know i mentioned this one right here
does have color-coded handle as you can
see
but you know once you get past 88 pounds
there's not a specific color for each
weight option so if you're somebody
who's strong enough to lift all of that
weight you might have a little bit of
difficulty because you know once again
there's not a specific color for each
weight option so that'd be an area of
improvement i guess you could say with
these kettlebells
they're also not uniform in size okay so
this 26 pound belt great size for
basically every single workout you'd
want to do with it as you go up and
weight the size is also going to
increase so
if you know uniform-sized kettlebells
are what you're looking for then i'd
suggest just going to get yourself some
competition kettlebells
and you know these really aren't cheap
i'm gonna dig into price here in just a
second don't worry but
you can definitely find some cheaper
ones out there but remember
when it comes to a high quality product
such as this you know you're paying for
that high quality which i have found to
be true with these kettlebells i think
you will as well and you know it's going
to be worth it in the long run you know
that high quality for that highest price
tag it's something that we really preach
about a lot
okay so let's talk about the money now
and what you can expect to spend on one
of these rogue kettlebells so as i
mentioned you can choose from nine
pounds up to 203 pounds
and as you probably can assume that nine
pound kettlebell is going to be your
cheapest option right around 35
this 26 pound bale is around 60 bucks
and that 203 pound kettlebell well
that's around 320
now
your total is gonna change
based off shipping and taxes it's gonna
vary on how fast you want it but also
which weight you decide to go with so
for example if you went with this 26
pound kettlebell
you know you're gonna have to pay an
extra 25
that's not that bad but if you went with
that 203 pound kettlebell well shipping
alone is going to cost you around 170
bucks and then tack on an additional 45
or so in taxes
you're looking at spending over 500 on
one single kettlebell
now that's definitely not cheap you can
obviously find some cheaper ones out
there those might not last you as long
but you know you could always go and
find yourself an adjustable kettlebell
system maybe even a kettle grip
attachment which rogue actually offers
one of those and that basically will
transform any existing dumbbells you
have
into a kettlebell but that's probably
not as good as the real thing
now at the end of the day i mean
these kettlebells the quality it's top
here meaning they should last you for a
very long time
[Music]
okay so let's talk about the build now
with these kettlebells as i said you
know they're not uniform in size so the
overall size of each bell is going to
increase but for now let's just focus on
the handle diameter okay so the 9 to 18
pound bells have a 1.2 inch handle
diameter this 26 pound kettlebell well
this handle diameter is 1.4 inches the
35 to 88 pound bells those have a handle
of 1.5 inches in diameter in the 97 to
203 have a 1.58 inch handle diameter
okay so i really like the color coding
here on these handles yeah it's pretty
common in most kettlebells but i will
say it pops out more in my opinion than
some other kettlebells i've used so
that's really nice too you know that
blue really contrasts with this matte
black powder coat really nice and
sticking with the powder coat you know
this gives you a really nice feel it's
got a really good grip on its own it's
also going to mix well with some chalk
too if that's something that you want to
use
i really like the flat base design right
here you know there's no seams there's
no ridges there's nothing that's going
to interfere with the kettlebell and
whatever surface you go to store it on
and that's really nice too it's gonna
make it really sturdy and these are
super durable okay so it's one single
piece of iron ore like i said there's no
plastic caps or plugs there's no welding
with the handle and the bell itself
so you don't have to worry about that
bell flying across the room
mid-swing you know it's not something
that you're not gonna have to worry
about here with these kettlebells so
that's really nice too because they're
gonna last you a really long time
[Music]
okay so let's talk about the features
now with these kettlebells once again
you know they do range from nine pounds
up to 203 pounds but for the sake of
this video we've got the 26 pounds
kettlebell
all right so the handle right here is
1.4 inches in diameter it's the only
kettlebell that features that diameter
just something worth remembering here
and i really like this color coding you
know it's really common yeah with
kettlebells but i don't think it's very
common they always pop out at you like
this does it's really nice to me it
makes it super easy to just see like oh
blue that is the 26 pound kettlebell
makes it really easily done but you know
you also have
your kilograms and pounds you know
engraved on the back side which is a
nice touch for you a little security
blanket i guess you could say just to
make sure you do in fact have the
correct weight you're looking for
and i've already talked about it i must
talk about it right now i'm going to
talk about it again here in a minute i'm
sure
i really like this flat base makes it
super easy to store you know this isn't
coated in rubber
there's nothing that's going to
interfere with the kettlebell and
whatever surface you got to store it on
so it's just gonna make it really easy
to store it if you don't have a storage
rack because those can tend to be pretty
expensive so you can easily you know set
this on the ground in the corner of your
room or on a shelf really whatever you
need to do
all right my people let's do a quick
walk around with this kettlebell once
again this is the 26 pound bell from
rogue so the handle is 1.4 inches in
diameter and this is the only one that
has that specific diameter okay so
at the base right here
nice and wide you can easily fit two
hands right here do any style two-handed
grip if you choose to do so
color coding is also right here blue
means this is 26 pounds but if you flip
it around on the back you'll see
both kilograms and pounds right there so
that's really nice too
the flat base right here is super nice
makes storage really easy there's no
seams there's no ridges there's nothing
in the way
and you know in terms of seams same goes
for the handle and the bell they're not
welded together because they're one
solid piece of iron and you can see that
up close there's nothing here you can
feel it i mean there's it's one big
piece right here i really like the
powder coat as well it looks good gives
it that nice matte black finish it like
i said it just looks good but
you get a really solid grip from it on
its own and it does work well with chalk
too if you care to use so so that's
really nice too a little bit of
versatility
[Music]
all right so who should purchase the
rogue kettlebells well since this is one
single piece of iron ore i think you're
really going to enjoy the durability of
these kettlebells since they're going to
last you
essentially a lifetime unless you do
something crazy and
somehow some way find a way to break it
this is going to be around for the long
haul and you know the powder coat here
it makes it look good it's going to look
good in your gym but really the
importance of it is the texture and the
grip that it provides gives you a pretty
good grip on its own but it's also going
to mix well with chalk you know so if
you want to use chalk you definitely can
do so with these kettlebells and once
again you know there's just so many
options for you to choose from from nine
pounds up to 203 pounds so i mean really
there's just an option out there for
everybody to pick from
[Music]
okay so what about the people who might
not want to purchase these kettlebells
well if your kettlebell is being uniform
in size it's something that's really
important to you you know you're not
going to get that here and if that is
the case then i would definitely suggest
finding yourself some competition
kettlebells because those are in fact
all the same size
if you're wanting your kettlebell to be
coated in rubber you know that's not
something you're going to find here that
technically does increase the chances of
causing damage to your floors inside
your home but that doesn't mean you can
just drop a rubber coated kettlebell
that could still cause some issues as
well so really don't want to do that
and let's be honest these are kind of
pricey especially if you purchase more
than one
so if budget is a problem for you i get
it
you know there's some cheaper ones out
there you can purchase they probably
won't last you as long so you know be
careful about that make sure
you know you know what they're being
made of before you go and buy it you can
also get yourself an adjustable
kettlebell system but those tend to cap
out at a weight you know that doesn't
come close to these
and you know you can always add a kettle
grip attachment to your dumbbells you
know i said earlier rogue does have a
kettle grip attachment you can buy but
the shape's not the same so it might
make some exercises a little bit awkward
[Music]
all right that's all i got for you today
on the rogue kettlebells these could be
the next solid addition to your home gym
a single piece of iron here it's gonna
make this super durable and you don't
have to worry about the connection
between the handle and the bell ever
coming loose over time so that's really
nice for you there the color-coded
handle makes it super easy to choose
which weight you're grabbing there's 18
different weight options for you to
choose from so it's really an option out
there for everybody and here it comes
again i told you it was coming this flat
base design right here is super nice in
my opinion yeah it makes it very stable
whenever you go to store it but you know
storage is made super easy because of
that even without a storage rack
thanks for watching everybody i hope
this video was helpful and that i was
able to teach you a little bit more
about these kettlebells what they have
to offer as always stay on the lookout
for my next review but in the meantime
head over to barbin.com you can read
more about these kettlebells just search
bar bend rogue kettlebell review
you can read everything i talked about
here today i'll see y'all next time
[Music]
you